Mykhailo Pustovit

Most recent position: Team Lead of Payments Mobile at WIX

Brief overview

Hello! My name is Mykhailo (Misha), and I'm a software engineer. I began my professional programming career in 2012, during my fifth year at the Computer Science faculty of Kyiv Polytechnic University, initially as **a Java developer**. Soon after, I transitioned to **Android development**. For the last 3 years, I've been working at **Wix**, focusing on **React Native** and **people management** as a **team lead**.

I have contributed to a variety of applications for app stores and been involved in **full-cycle development** - from initial estimation to release and support. I have extensive experience as an **Android** (Kotlin/Java) and **React Native** (JS/TS) developer. Additionally, I have experience with **Swift** (SDK creation and maintenance, minor UI features), **team process facilitation** (Scrum Master and Team Lead roles), and **extreme programming practices** (TDD, CI, pair programming).

Contacts

Email: pustovitm@gmail.com Telegram: +380683999318 GitHub repo: https://github.com/lampapos

Mobile phone: (+380) 68 399 93 18

Areas of Expertise

- Mobile application (SDK/libraries) development
 - Android (Kotlin/Java)
 - React Native (JS/TS)
 - iOS (Swift)
- Dev team work facilitation
 - Communication with product owners
 - People management (1-1s, growth plans, etc)
 - Estimation and planning
 - Had a scrum master role
 - Extreme programming practices (TDD, pair programming, CI/DI)
- Team Management and Tech guidance of 3rd party development teams

Experience

Team Lead of Payments Mobile at Wix — Apr 2022 – Present
 Leading the mobile payments team and responsible for everything related to payment processes
 across Wix's family of React Native applications for site owners and visitors. This includes
 handling checkout screens, transaction details, and other payment-related features.

Apps: Google Play, App Store

• Senior Mobile Engineer at Wix - Dec 2020 - Apr 2022

Worked on the **React Native** apps at Wix, focusing on providing services for site owners and visitors. Collaborated on various aspects of mobile app development, including payment processes.

• Lead Mobile Engineer at INTELITY - Sep 2018 - May 2020

Led a team of four developers in creating custom applications for hotels and door lock solutions. **Achievements:**

- Built CI tools for white-label applications (one code base multiple apps with different resources)
- Supported and maintained multiplatform SDK (Android, iOS, React Native) for third-party development teams
- Facilitated the Scrum process

Apps: Google Play

• Senior Android Developer at KEYPR - Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

Developed complex solutions for the hospitality industry, including custom Android firmware.

Achievements:

- Modified system components like System UI, Launcher, and default applications
- Developed a set of apps for hotel services: maps, compendiums, custom daydream app for hotel ads
- Created a custom app distribution system and tools for hardware monitoring and management

Apps: Google Play

• Android Developer at Stanfy - Feb 2012 - Apr 2017

Worked on several projects, including:

• **Voicebase:** A sound recording app with challenges such as audio recording, sync with server, and complete UI/REST client development.

App: Google Play

■ "Право Украины" (Law of Ukraine): A tablet app with a collection of Ukrainian laws.

Challenges: Worked on a large DB, a sophisticated webview with custom CSS and JS, and UI widgets.

App: Google Play

• **Kinopoisk for Android:** Contributed to the maintenance and development of new features for the **Kinopoisk** app.

App: Google Play

Junior Java Developer at NCube Ltd — Aug 2011 – Jan 2012
 Worked on undisclosed projects under NDA.

Developers community

- Lecturer of Software testing course at NTUU "KPI" (as a volunteer)
- Moderator at <u>KyivAndroidDevClub</u>
- Speaker at
 - KyivAndroidDevClub meetups
 - Stanfy MadCode webinars
 - GDG DevFest 2016
 - Dev at work: Mobile meetup

Languages

- English Professional working proficiency
- o Ukrainian Native or bilingual proficiency

Education

National Technical University of Ukraine 'Kyiv Polytechnic Institute.'
 Master, Computer Science, 2007 - 2013, Graduated with honors

Personal details

Birthday April 06, 1990

Tech skills

- Main language: Java/Kotlin, JS/TS
- Languages (basic knowledge/have some experience): Swift, Golang, C/C++
- o Development tools: IntellyJ Idea (Android Studio, Web Storm), XCode, Eclipse, Vim
- Programming theory:
 - Basic algorithms and data structures
 - GoF patterns
 - OOP design principles
 - Basics of functional programming
- Strong knowledge of:
 - Core Java/Kotlin
 - Android SDK
 - Mobile apps architeture
 - REST clients
- Has experience in/with:
 - Testing/TDD: Junit, Mockito, Robolectric, AssertJ, Cuckoo

■ **DB:** SQL, JDBC, NoSQL (Mongo, Firebase)

■ **Text processing tools:** RegExp

Java concurrency

• Reactive programming: RxJava, RxAndroid, RxSwift

 User interfaces: Android Standard UI elements, AWT, Swing, Java2D, Qt, JS(Bootstrap, Angular)

• Android app architectures: MVP, MVVM, Flux, Clean Architecture, etc

■ Build tools: Gradle, Maven, Fastlane

■ Version control: GIT, SVN

■ **Web:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript (on basic level)

■ **DI:** Dagger *, Android Annotations, Guice, Koin

■ **Graphic editing:** basic skils

■ CI: Jenkins/Pipeline, docker

• Network communication: REST clients (Retrofit, OkHttp, Apache HTTP client), GSON

■ **Hybrid mobile frameworks:** ReactNative

• Agile frameworks: Scrum

• Worked in these environments: Mac OS X, Linux (Ubuntu), Windows